in this lecture will take a look at two AWS services
for compliance and audit.
So the first one is called as AWS artifact
and AWS artifact provides on demand access
to AWS compliance documentation and AWS agreement.
So you can think of AWS artifact as a portal
where all the compliance documentation
related to AWS services is stored.
So you can download AWS security and compliance documents
such as ISO certification, PC IDSS, SOC report
through either the console, AWS console,
or if you are being evaluated by an auditor,
you can create an IM role for the auditor
through which he can go to this AWS artifact service
and review the documentation.
Okay, now let me just quickly show you
through the console, AWS artifacts.
Okay, IM on the AWS console.
So let me just search for AWS artifacts.
So I'm on the AWS artifact service
and you can see here agreement reports and notification.
So we just click on report
and let's say I'm trying to be compliant with PC IDSS.
So I can just search for PCI
and you will see all the compliance reports from AWS
are within this service.
So you can see your PCI 3DS attestation compliance
and then you can just go ahead and download these if required.
Okay, so I think this pretty straightforward.
Now let's go and take a look at the second service,
which is AWS audit manager.
So AWS audit manager continuously audit your AWS usage
to assess risk and compliance with regulations
and industry standards.
So what AWS audit manager would do is
so it will look at all the AWS services
that you are using within the account
and then assess whether you are being compliant
with the regulation in your industry.
So it also provides some pre-built frameworks
for well-known industry standards and regulations
such as HIPAA, GDPR, PCI DSS and maps
to customer AWS resources and SSS compliance.
So now we can see the AWS audit manager
is not just validating whether AWS services are compliant.
It's looking at your usage of these services
and whether they are compliant with the industry standard
and regulations such as HIPAA, PCI DSS, et cetera.
So how does it ensure you are compliant?
It integrates and collects data
from various AWS services such as cloud trail, security hub
and others.
And we'll take a look at cloud trail and some of these services
but what it essentially does is
it will take alerts from these different services
and then map them to the pre-built frameworks
for well-known industries and see if there's any deviation.
And finally, AWS audit manager also assists
in gathering and preparing evidence for audits.
So rather than manually collecting evidence
for your audits, it can help automate that process.
Now let's just go to the console and just take a quick look.
So let me just search for audit manager.
And you can see AWS audit manager.
Okay, now I am on the AWS audit manager.
And now we can see on the left hand side,
let me just click on assessments.
And here you can see under assessments,
access all your past and current assessments.
You can select an assessment to review the evidence
collected and generate assessment report.
So we just click on create assessment
and let me just give it a name demo.
And then it shows where the final assessment should be sent.
So you can provide a path for S3 bucket
and then you have to select the framework.
So you can see all the frameworks.
Let me just click on this fedram
and you can see here type standard
and it has about 325 controls on which it evaluates your compliance.
So let me just click on this.
So on the left hand side, you can see access control
that about 43 policies that you need to be compliant with.
And on the right hand side, you can see the data sources.
So if you want to be compliant with EC21,
what the audit manager will do is it will gather data
from AWS EPA calls your AWS cloud trail service,
AWS config service, it'll be security hub service.
And then map if you are being compliant.
And in few cases like here being compliant with AC1,
you have to gather the evidence manually.
So hopefully it's clear to you how this audit manager works.
So you can select the industry framework,
then it is going to ingest the data from these different
AWS services and then do the mapping and generate a report.
So hopefully you are clear on the difference
between AWS artifact and AWS audit manager
because it's most likely going to be evaluated in the exam.
I'll see you in the next lecture.
Thank you.